<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Doubt on Ajay</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/doubt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Doubt on Ajay</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 22:50:50 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/doubt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DSA or Dev: A beginner&#39;s guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/devordsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 22:50:50 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/devordsa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;DISCLAIMER: IT&amp;rsquo;S ALL JUST MY OPINION AND EXPERIENCE, PLEASE DONT&amp;rsquo;T QUOTE ME ON ANYTHING I BLABBER HERE&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked a lot of time by several of my friends that what should they do as freshmen, DSA or Development? &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the people haven&amp;rsquo;t done any programming until now, please just focus on programming fundamentals for now - PAR KIDHAR SE??? (translation: &amp;ldquo;but from where???&amp;rdquo;). If you have a ton of time(just me being illogically hyper), I&amp;rsquo;d anyday recommend you to go with CS50x by David Malan, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn a lot about the fundamentals of CS(CS != programming). But again, if you just wanna get into programming ASAP, just learn C++(just spell it as &amp;ldquo;cpp&amp;rdquo;, you&amp;rsquo;ll sound better I promise). Yeah yeah - &amp;ldquo;WHY C++, WHY NOT PYTHON, JAVASCRIPT OR C?&amp;rdquo;: I don&amp;rsquo;t know, I just love the language and I&amp;rsquo;ll promote whatever I love(not funny). OK, jokes aside - Firstly about C - You &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; go with C if you want, it&amp;rsquo;s just a subset of C++ in a way, but if I were you, I&amp;rsquo;d have gone with C++ because it&amp;rsquo;s just C, but with better abstraction(thus making the syntax less overwhelming in the beginning), it has OOP if you wanna go with it, it has STL which is gonna make your life SO-MUCH easier if you&amp;rsquo;ll go(which you will, eventually) with competitive programming(or DSA) and of course, both C and C++ are close to the machine.&#xA;Now not Java? - Again, you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; go with Java, but if I were you(déjà vu, right?), I&amp;rsquo;d have gone with C++ just because C++ gives you a freedom of style, while Java forces you into OOP from day one(Unless you&amp;rsquo;re OOP-fanatic, I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone would want their style defined by the language itself). Also, C++ has a large CP/DSA community, and finding resources in C++ is damn easy as what I&amp;rsquo;ve observed, and yeah, everyone hates Java, so just don&amp;rsquo;t bother with it(hope you get the satire).&#xA;Now why not Javascript and Python? Simply because they spoon-feed you. They are high-level languages, certainly not close to machine, thus making you do things, but with so-much abstraction such that you don&amp;rsquo;t get to know how&amp;rsquo;s the thing really working behind the scene. You don&amp;rsquo;t get to know &amp;ldquo;WHY&amp;rdquo; and it&amp;rsquo;s something you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do when you are a beginner. Of course they&amp;rsquo;re useful languages and they are everywhere, but please, go with them only after you&amp;rsquo;re done with the fundamentals with a low-level language like C++.&#xA;Now where to learn C++? If you are a doc person, please follow learncpp.com by heart, and if you&amp;rsquo;re a video-tutorial person, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend TheCherno&amp;rsquo;s YouTube playlist for cpp. For the beginners, just go with the YouTube playlist because it has less friction and you&amp;rsquo;ll actually not lose motivation in the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
